Doll & Richards Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Doll & Richards gallery records
1863-1978, bulk 1902-1960s
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Doll & Richards gallery
82.7 linear feet
The records of the Doll & Richards gallery of Boston measure 82.7 linear feet and date from 1863 to 1978, with the bulk of the material dating from 1902-1960s. Extensive financial and sales records, inventory records, and correspondence and letter books provide a detailed account of the business operations and sales of the gallery. Also found are notes and research files on artists and paintings, business and legal records, exhibition catalogs, six exhibition scrapbooks, printed materials, and photographs. Significant correspondents include John Chetcuti, Robert Freiman, Lloyd Goodrich, Tod Lindenmuth, Macbeth Galleries, William Meyerowitz, Museum of Fine Arts Boston, Stanley Woodward, and Andrew Wyeth, among many others.
Provenance
The Doll & Richards records were donated to the Archives of American Art in numerous accessions between 1973 and 1979 by Jeanne and Paul Sylva, who purchased the gallery in 1973, and by former employee Wendell Zoehler.
Separated Material
A daguerroteype of Gaetano Cardinal Bedini received with the records was transferred to the Smithsonian National Portrait Gallery on May 24, 2004.
Related Material
Among the other resources relating to the Doll & Richards gallery in the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview with Wendell Zoehler conducted by Robert Brown on April 14 and April 27, 1978.
Alternative Forms Available
Portions of the collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels 350-368 (letterpress copybooks) and NDR1-NDR4 (exhibition catalogs) at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. The arrangement of the materials on microfilm may differ from the current arrangement.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Historical Note
The Doll & Richards gallery originated in Boston in 1866 as an art gallery and framing shop owned by Charles E. Hendrickson, E. Adam Doll, and Joseph Dudley Richards. The gallery was a well-known Boston establishment for over 100 years that represented William Stanley Haseltine, Winslow Homer, William Morris Hunt, and Andrew Wyeth, among many other notable American painters, sculptors, and printmakers.
In 1870 Hendrickson retired and the gallery became Doll & Richards. After the untimely death of Doll in 1880, Richards purchased Doll's interest in the firm, retaining the gallery's well-known name. Under Richards' direction, the gallery prospered. Richards promoted the works of painter Winslow Homer, developing a market for his watercolors in Boston. He incorporated the gallery in 1902 and served as the treasurer and financier until his death in 1922 at 80 years old. The gallery then reorganized; Arthur McKean, who joined in 1911, became manager, and J.L. (Joe) Richards became treasurer. Fergus Turner, who joined the firm as a salesman in 1885 and became president in 1902, retained his role as president until 1938.
Over the century the gallery showcased contempory American artists, including William Morris Hunt, Dodge McKnight, William Stanley Haseltine, Laura Coombs Hills, Eliot O'Hara, Joseph Lindon Smith, Stanley Woodward, and Andrew Wyeth. The gallery also consigned paintings, prints, and objects from other major art galleries including Azeez Khayat Gallery, Kennedy Galleries, M. Knoedler and Co., Macbeth Gallery, Victor D. Spark, and Victor Waddington Galleries (Dublin, Ireland). According to long-time employee Wendell Zoehler (employed from 1929-1966), Doll & Richards' primary clientele came from the Social Register. In the summer months when wealthy Bostonians typically vacationed outside of the city, Doll & Richards remained open for tourists, many of whom became regular seasonal customers of the gallery.
The gallery experienced financial difficulties in the 1930s, leading to bankruptcy. Doll & Richards was purchased by McKean and incorporated in Maine in 1941. McKean sold Doll & Richards in 1962 to Maurice Goldberg; at this time none of the remaining family or staff were connected with the gallery. In 1973, the gallery was sold to Jeanne and Paul Sylva and closed.
Although the gallery always remained in the vicinity of Boston Common, it relocated numerous times over the years. In 1871 the gallery moved from 28 Summer Street to 145 Tremont Street. In 1878, the gallery remodeled and occupied the entire two-story building at 2 Park Street, renting out the second floor, known as the Hawthorne Room, for lectures. After thirty years on Park Street, Doll & Richards relocated to Newbury Street in 1908, beginning a succession of moves down Newbury Street approximately every twenty years, finally to 172 Newbury Street in 1962.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Doll & Richards gallery of Boston measure 82.7 linear feet and date from 1863 to 1978, with the bulk of the material dating from 1902-1960s. Extensive financial and sales records, inventory records, and correspondence and letter books provide a detailed account of the business operations and sales of the gallery. Also found are notes and research files on artists and paintings, business and legal records, exhibition catalogs, six exhibition scrapbooks, printed materials, and photographs. The bulk of the collection dates from 1902 when the gallery was incorporated and new books were begun. According to gallery employee Wendell Zoehler, many records from the 19th century were discarded and periodically, especially when the gallery moved, other records were discarded.
Incoming and outgoing correspondence documents sales, consignments, appraisals, exhibitions, and inquiries by artists and others to Doll & Richards for over a century. Significant correspondents include artists John Chetcuti, Robert Freiman, Tod Lindenmuth, William Meyerowitz, Dwight Shepler, Elizabeth O'Neill Verner, Stanley Woodward, Andrew Wyeth, and others. Additional correspondents include Lloyd Goodrich from Whitney Museum of American Art, Azeez Khayat Gallery, Macbeth Galleries, Kleemann Galleries, and the Museum of Fine Arts in Boston. There is one letter from George Inness (1866). Outgoing correspondence is limited to 46 volumes of letterpress copybooks dating from 1930-1967.
Notes and research files primarily consist of compiled information about artists in which Doll & Richards dealt. These include card files related to the provenance of paintings by Winslow Homer and William Stanley Haseltine, and a book about Winslow Homer with notations by Zoehler about the sale of paintings.
Administrative and business records of general daily operations include an address book, meeting minutes, miscellaneous lists and notes, and a large card file of contacts with clients, consignors, artists, and businesses. A detailed description of the gallery's operations by Zoehler is also found here. Legal records include contracts, agreements, certificates of stock, certificates of copyrights, and photocopies of founding documents.
Although there are limited records prior to 1902, the financial records provide comprehensive detail of the gallery's financial transactions from the turn of the century through the early 1970s. Volumes of financial ledgers provide details of artwork bought, sold, and consigned; order forms for sales, framing, restoration, and shipping; gallery expenditures and salaries; records of client purchases; and other affairs. Many of the financial records are indexed and cross-referenced, offering researchers complex but rich documentation. The financial records should be consulted with the numerous inventory records that provide detailed information about the stock of art work held at the gallery. Inventory records also include documentation about the frames held by the gallery from the mid-1880s-1950. The gallery used sometimes complex codes to index and cross reference sales and stock. When known, these codes have been outlined in the more detailed series desciptions below, or filed within the appropriate boxes.
The history of Doll & Richards' exhibitions from the 1880s-1968 are documented in six disassembled bound volumes that contained exhibition catalogs and announcements. There are also additional loose catalogs and announcements. Additional printed materials include newspaper clippings related to exhibitions and the gallery and seven scrapbooks related to Doll & Richards' exhibitions from 1909-1943.
The bulk of the black and white photographs in the collection are of works of art by artists that Doll & Richards exhibited. There are only a handful of photographs of other subject matter, but include images of the gallery spaces at 2 Park Street, 71 Newbury, and 138 Newberry; and of artists.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as nine series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1863-1972, bulk 1930s-1972 (Boxes 1-14; 14 linear feet)
Series 2: Notes and Research Files, 1880s-1978, bulk 1930s-1960s (Boxes 15-16, 78; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 3: Business Records, circa 1866-1978, bulk 1910s-1960s (Boxes 16-18; 1.9 linear feet)
Series 4: Legal Records, 1863-1906, 1941-1962 (Boxes 18, 78; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 5: Financial Records, 1871-1973, bulk 1902-1969 (Boxes 18-69, 79, BV81-112; 55 linear feet)
Series 6: Inventory Records, 1881-1969, bulk 1900s-1940s (Boxes 69-70, BV113-128; 2.3 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Materials, circa 1880s-1968, bulk 1890s-1960s (Boxes 70-75; 4.9 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographs, circa 1880s-1960s (Boxes 75-78; 2 linear feet)
Series 9: Scrapbooks, 1908-1968, bulk 1908-1943 (Boxes 77, 80; 1.1 linear feet)
The records have been arranged according to the original order maintained by the gallery. Bound volumes containing exhibition catalogs glued to the internal spines have been disbound for preservation and proper housing.
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Haseltine, William Stanley, 1835-1900; Homer, Winslow, 1836-1910
Subjects-Topical:
Art, American; Art dealers -- Massachusetts -- Boston; Art galleries, Commercial -- Massachusetts -- Boston
Types of Materials:
Financial records; Photographs; Scrapbooks
Names:
Chetcuti, John; Freiman, Robert; Goodrich, Lloyd, 1897-; Lindenmuth, Tod; Meyerowitz, William, 1887-1981; Shepler, Dwight, 1905-; Verner, Elizabeth O'Neill, 1883-1979; Woodward, Stanley Wingate, 1890-1970; Wyeth, Andrew, 1917-; Zoehler, Wendell H., 1907-1989; Azeez Khayat Gallery; Kleemann Galleries; Macbeth Gallery; Museum of Fine Arts, Boston
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1863-1972, bulk 1930s-1972, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-14; 14 linear feet)
  Incoming correspondence is from artists, collectors, consigners, suppliers and vendors, galleries, and museums. Incoming correspondence is in chronological and alphabetical order. Outgoing correspondence is contained in 46 letterpress copybooks. Correspondence includes topics such as inquiries into appraisals, artwork sales and consignments, framing and shipping arrangements, and exhibitions.
  The series is arranged as three subseries:
  1.1: Chronological Correspondence, 1863-1972
  1.2: Alphabetical Correspondence, 1921-1971
  1.3: Letterpress Copybooks, 1930-1967
  Because the collection was minimally processed, chronological and alphabetical correspondence have not been merged.
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1863-1972, 1.1:
    Significant correspondents include artists John Chetcuti, Robert Freiman, Tod Lindenmuth, William Meyerowitz, Dwight Shepler, Elizabeth O'Neill Verner, Stanley Woodward, Andrew Wyeth, and others; Lloyd Goodrich from Whitney Museum of American Art, Azeez Khayat Gallery, Macbeth Galleries, Kleemann Galleries, and the Museum of Fine Arts in Boston. There is one letter from George Inness (1866). Also found among the correspondence is scattered artwork lists, exhibition price lists, and photographs. Items are arranged in chronological order within each folder.
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1863-1900 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1903-1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1918-1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1939, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Correspondence, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1940, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
    - Correspondence, 1941, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    - Correspondence, 1942, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 19-21)
    - Correspondence, 1943, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 22-26)
    - Correspondence, 1944, (8 folders) (Box 1, Folder 27-34)
    - Correspondence, 1945, (8 folders) (Box 1, Folder 35-42)
    - Correspondence, 1946, (10 folders) (Box 1, Folder 43-52)
    - Correspondence, [1947] (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence, 1947, (11 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-11)
    - Correspondence, 1948, (12 folders) (Box 2, Folder 12-23)
    - Correspondence, 1949, (11 folders) (Box 2, Folder 24-34)
    - Correspondence, 1950, (12 folders) (Box 2, Folder 35-46)
    - Correspondence, 1951, (10 folders) (Box 2, Folder 47-56)
    - Correspondence, 1952, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 57-58)
    - Correspondence, 1952, (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-10)
    - Correspondence, 1953, (9 folders) (Box 3, Folder 11-19)
    - Correspondence, 1954, (11 folders) (Box 3, Folder 20-30)
    - Correspondence, 1955, (7 folders) (Box 3, Folder 31-37)
    - Correspondence, 1956, (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 38-47)
    - Correspondence, 1957, (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 48-57)
    - Correspondence, [1958] (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence, 1958, (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 59-68)
    - Correspondence, [1959] (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Correspondence, 1959, (11 folders) (Box 3, Folder 70-80)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1960, (12 folders) (Box 4, Folder 2-13)
    - Correspondence, [1961] (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1961, (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 15-18)
    - Correspondence, [1962] (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1962, (10 folders) (Box 4, Folder 20-29)
    - Correspondence, [1963] (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1963, (12 folders) (Box 4, Folder 31-42)
    - Correspondence, 1964, (12 folders) (Box 4, Folder 43-54)
    - Correspondence, [1965] (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence, 1965, (12 folders) (Box 4, Folder 56-67)
    - Correspondence, [1966] (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Correspondence, 1966, (12 folders) (Box 4, Folder 69-80)
    - Correspondence, [1967] (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Correspondence, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 82-83)
    - Correspondence, 1967, (10 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-10)
    - Correspondence, 1968, (10 folders) (Box 5, Folder 11-20)
    - Correspondence, [1969] (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1969, (10 folders) (Box 5, Folder 22-31)
    - Correspondence, [1970s] (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, 1970, (8 folders) (Box 5, Folder 33-40)
    - Correspondence, 1971, (5 folders) (Box 5, Folder 41-45)
    - Correspondence, 1972, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 46-47)
  - Alphabetical Correspondence, 1921-1971, 1.2:
    Significant correspondents include Kennedy Galleries, Azeez Khayat Gallery, and Eliot and Shirley O'Hara. Some of the correspondents in this subseries are also found in the Chronological Correspondence. Folders are arranged alphabetically by name, then chronologically within the folder. Undated materials are filed at the front of the folder.
    - Bardolet, J. Coll, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Connaway, Jay and Louise, circa 1948-1963, 1968, (5 folders) (Box 5, Folder 49-53)
    - Courvoisier Gallery (San Francisco, CA), 1938-1942, (9 folders) (Box 5, Folder 54-62)
    - de Botton, Jean, 1966, January - 1967, February, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 63-64)
    - Egginton, Frank, circa 1939-1971, (7 folders) (Box 5, Folder 65-71)
    - Fulop, Karoly, 1931-1938 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Hekking, William M., 1955-1960 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Kennedy Galleries (New York, NY), 1936-1937, 1944-1961, 1967, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 74-77)
    - Azeez Khayat Gallery (New York, NY), 1927-1934, 1938, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 78-81)
    - Azeez Khayat Gallery (New York, NY), 1947-1952 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Azeez Khayat Gallery [Susette Khayat] (New York, NY), 1953-1955, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
    - Azeez Khayat Gallery [Ancient Arts Gallery] (New York, NY), 1956-1966, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 4-7)
    - M. Knoedler and Co. (New York, NY), 1943-1965, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 8-10)
    - Leighton, Clare, 1929-1959 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Macbeth Galleries (New York, NY), 1950-1953 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Macknight, Dodge, 1936-1945 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Mundy, Ethel Frances, 1943-1956 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - O'Hara, Eliot and Shirley, circa 1932-1940, 1947-1969, (9 folders) (Box 6, Folder 15-23)
    - Parsons, Harold W., 1921-1922 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Plowden, Helen H. [William Stanley Haseltine], circa 1936-1966, (14 folders) (Box 6, Folder 25-38)
    - Smith, Mrs. Joseph Lindon (Corinna), circa 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Spark, Victor D. (New York, NY), 1943-1965, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 40-44)
    - Vidal, Margarita Hahn, 1963-1971, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 45-46)
    - Victor Waddington Galleries (Dublin, Ireland), 1951-1962 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Young Hunter, John, 1936-1943, 1955-1963, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 48-49)
  - Letterpress Copybooks, 1930-1967, 1.3:
    Letterpress copybooks provide a record of outgoing correspondence printed on carbon tissue paper. Each volume contains an index to correspondents.
    - Volume 56 [incorrectly labeled 59], September 22, 1930 - January 23, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Volume 57, January 23 - July 6, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Volume 58, July 6, 1931 - January 6, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Volume 59, January 6 - July 26, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Volume 60, July 26, 1932 - February 21, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Volume 61, February 21 - November 1, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Volume 62, November 1, 1933 - May 23, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Volume 63, May 24, 1934 - January 16, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Volume 64, January 16 - July 19, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Volume 65, July 19, 1935 - February 4, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Volume 66, February 4 - September 29, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Volume 67, September 29, 1936 - April 7, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Volume 68, April 8 - October 28, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Volume 69, October 29, 1937 - March 4, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Volume 70, March 4 - September 8, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Volume 71, September 8, 1938 - January 7, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Volume 72, January 7 - May 8, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Volume 73, May 9 - November 7, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Volume 74, November 7, 1939 - March 18, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Volume 75, March 18 - August 30, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Volume 76, August 30, 1940 - February 6, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Volume 77, February 6 - July 18, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Volume 78, July 18, 1941 - March 19, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Volume 79, March 20, 1942 - February 26, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Volume 80, February 27, 1943 - March 20, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Volume 81, March 21, 1944 - April 4, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Volume 82, April 4, 1945 - June 7, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Volume 83, June 7, 1946 - April 29, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Volume 84, April 29, 1947 - February 10, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Volume 85, February 10 - November 12, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Volume 86, November 12, 1948 - October 3, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Volume 87, October 3, 1949 - July 17, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Volume 88, July 18, 1950 - July 10, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Volume 89, July 11, 1951 - April 26, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Volume 90, April 26, 1952 - April 14, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Volume 91, April 15, 1953 - April 28, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Volume 92, April 28, 1954 - April 13, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Volume 93, April 14, 1955 - April 23, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Volume 94, April 24, 1956 - April 15, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Volume 95, April 15, 1957 - May 7, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Volume 96, May 8, 1958 - May 7, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Volume 97, May 7, 1959 - May 18, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Volume 98, May 18, 1960 - July 31, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Volume 99, July 31, 1961 - May 1, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Volume 100, May 9, 1963 - February 1, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Volume 101, February 8, 1966 - March 2, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Notes and Research Files, 1880s-1978, bulk 1930s-1960s, Series 2:; (Boxes 15-16, 78; 1.2 linear feet)
  Notes and research files include research compiled by Doll & Richards on artists and paintings in which the gallery exhibited or were interested in. Materials are varied and include clippings; compiled biographies; exhibition announcements and catalogs, many with notations; notecards on reported sales of paintings with references to works by Homer and Sargent; miscellaneous notes; price lists; scattered photographs; and a book about Winslow Homer with marginalia by Wendell Zoehler regarding exhibitions and sales.
  Also found are two sets of card files: Arthur McKean's card file for Winslow Homer paintings, and Wendell Zoehler's card file for William Stanley Haseltine paintings. The original order of each card file has been retained. The Winslow Homer card file is separated into oils and watercolors/drawings, and then arranged alphabetically by the title of the artwork. Each of the approximately 700 cards contains information such as when it was received and from whom, sale price and net (in code), date of sale, identification number related to the records of works ledger books (found in Series 6, Inventory), sales and work order form number (found in Subseries 5.2, Financial Records, Sales), when and where it was exhibited, a description of the painting, and a bibliography. An explanation of the sale price code is filed with the cards. The William Stanley Haseltine card file is arranged alphabetically by institution or buyer name and includes such information as purchaser, size, price, and sales and work order form number.
  Additional scattered research materials about artwork are also found in the Series 8, Photographs.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Allston, Washington, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Sketches of Artists and Portrait Subjects, 1880s-1960s (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Sketches of Contemporary Artists, circa 1920s-1972 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Card File for William Stanley Haseltine, circa 1950s-1978, (shoebox) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Card File for William Stanley Haseltine - Unfolded Materials, circa 1950s-1978 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Card File for Winslow Homer Paintings, circa 1900s-1950s, (shoebox) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Card File for Winslow Homer Paintings - Price Code Instructions, circa 1900s-1950s (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Connaway, Jay, 1948-1965 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - de Botton, Jean, 1956-1957, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition and Sales Notes, circa 1929-1958 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Harriman, Mary, circa 1961-1962 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Haseltine, William Stanley, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Haseltine, William Stanley, 1953-1959 (Box 15, Folder 13)